回想
（ルーク）約束だよ　カイト。
悪いのは　パズルじゃない。
Promise me, Kaito.
It's never the puzzle's fault.
裏切るのは　いつでも
それを作った人間。
It's always the person who makes it that betrays us.
僕たちだけは信じてあげよう。
パズルのことを。
We should at least believe in the puzzles, okay?
Yeah.
It's a promise then.
約束だよ　２人の。
うん！　約束だ。
Yeah. It's a promise.
ルーク。
（ソウジ）呼んだ？
あっ！
Rook...
Hello there.
あ～っ！　軸川先輩！　いつから？
いつからでしょう？
Jikugawa, how long have you been there?
Long enough.
何か　用かよ。
君に　新たに
パズルの解放の依頼が来てるんだ。
Do you want something?
You've got a new puzzle release request.
日曜日　空けといてね。
ウン。
Leave your schedule open on Sunday.
カイト君？
いい加減にしろ。
Kaito?
I've had enough of this. I don't care about
Sage Puzzles or treasures or anything else.
賢者のパズルだか　財だか
知らねえけど　俺には関係ねえ。
分かったよ。
Okay then.
今回のパズルは　カイト君にも
無理じゃないかとは思ってたんで→
I was thinking it'd be too hard for you anyway...
しかたないな。　じゃあね。
See you later.
ウッ。　どんなパズルなんだよ？！
What kind of puzzle is it?
よかった。　カイト君なら
やってくれると思ってた。
Wonderful! I knew you'd do it!
なっ…　俺は　まだ　やるとは…。
I didn't say I would!
I've already prepared the partner you'll need for this puzzle.
今回のパズルは　パートナーが必要になると
思って　用意しといたから。
パートナー？　何だ　そりゃ？
Partner? What do you mean?
第２美術室に行けば　会えるよ。
ダビンチの称号を与えられし者に。
Go to the second art studio and see for yourself.
The one who holds the title of Da Vinci.
ダビンチ？
Da Vinci?
kimi no nounai he shinnyuu nemutteiru sukima ni
I infiltrate your brain while you're sleeping.
Baby, open the gate!
fukuzatsu sugi sekyuriti kakusareru to abakitaku naru
The security's too tough, but I want to expose what's hidden.
barabara ni chirabatteiru pasuwado wo hiroi atsume
I gather the pieces of the shattered password.
kakushin ni sematte iku sono shoutai wo misete
I get close to the core. Show me who you really are!
kantan ni kuria dekinai saki nante motto yomenai
I can't clear it easily. I can't even see what lies ahead.
kaidoku fukanou sumairu kikenna pazuru
Your indecipherable smile is a hazardous puzzle.
rokku sareta doa aru nara zutto tataite miru beki kazana hiraku wa
When you see a locked door, you should just hit it until a crack opens.
eien ni hodokenai nazo nanka wa nai
There's no mystery that lasts forever!
makiokosu, it's a supernova
I made it, it's a supernova!
tobikiri shigekitekina hirameki wo agemashou
Let's flash so bright it'd hurt!
Misskey-Misskey La-Tu-Ma
yume no naka it's a supernova
In my dreams, it's a supernova!
watashi wa sou brain diver
Yeah, I'm the brain diver!
kimi ga sagashi motometeru kotae ni nareru made
Until I can find the answer you're looking for...
Brain diver!
The Girl of the Secret Room
（ノノハ）日曜日か？　どうしよう。
Sunday, huh? What should we do?
その日　私　ソフトボール部から
助っ人　頼まれてるんだよねぇ。
The Softball Club asked me to help them out.
何で　ノノハが悩むんだよ。
そっか！　確かに。
I can't see how this is your problem.
You're right, you should change partners every now and then.
たまには　私以外のパートナーと
組むのもいいかも。
断りに行くんだって
言ってんだろ。
I told you I'm going to refuse.
…つうか　お前　いつから
俺のパートナーになったんだよ。
And since when are you my partner?
うふん。　そうよね。
このままじゃ　カイト→
Yeah right, you couldn't live without me!
いつまでたっても
ノノハ離れ　できないもんね。
何だよ　その「親の苦労」みたいな
発言は…。
You sound like my mother.
（アイリ）カイト先輩　ノノハ先輩と楽しそう。
Kaito is having so much fun with Nonoha.
私もパズルの話題で
もっと自分をアピールしなきゃ！
I should get closer to him by talking about puzzles!
なんだか　気味が悪い…。
This place is really creepy.
お化けとか出たりしないよね。
やめろよ。
There won't be ghosts or anything, right?
Cut it out.
うっ！　何　あれ？
What's that?
まさか　おば…。　ちょっと　カイト！
Don't tell me... it's a gh-gho-
Wait, Kaito!
カイト！
カー　カー！　あっ？！
Kaito?!
えっ？！　女の子？
Huh? A girl?
（アナ）アナが思うに…
小鳥さんたちとのおしゃべり→
I think... you shouldn't have interrupted my chat with the birdies.
邪魔しちゃいけないんだな。
えっ？！
ふっ　今日は　ここまで。
そう思うでしょう。
でしょって。
This is it for today, right?
Why are you asking me?
でしょう？
さあ…。
Right?
Well...
ダメ～！
あ～！
No!
あっ！　目が！　目が…　あ～！
My eyes! My eyes!
思い出した。　入学してから　ずっと
授業にも出ないで→
I just remembered...
There's this rumor about a student who never goes to class
美術室に閉じこもっている
生徒がいるって噂。
and just hangs around the art studios.
すごい芸術の
才能の持ち主なんだって。
They say she's a real art genius.
I think her name is Ana Gram.
名前は　確か　アナ・グラム。
アナ・グラム…。
Ana Gram?
それが　ダビンチの正体か？
≫（アイリ）カイト先輩！
She's Da Vinci then?
Kaito! This jigsaw puzzle is too difficult for me!
このジグソーパズル　アイリには難しくて。
よかったら　一緒に解いて。
Would you help me solve it?
あちゃ～！
あっ　レオレオ！
Ah Leo-Leo!
Leo-Leo?
レオナルド・ダビンチの絵のパズル。
It's a puzzle from a painting of Leonardo Da Vinci!
アナ　レオレオ　大好き！
I love Leo-Leo!
バラバラのピース見ただけで
絵柄を認識しちゃったの？！
You recognized the painting from the scattered pieces?
一瞬で　パズルを脳内で
組み立てたってのか？！
Are you telling me you solved that in a second?
（アナ）でも　このジグソー
完成しないと思うな。
But I think this puzzle can't be completed.
うん？！
ピースが１個　足りないから。
One piece is missing.
（アイリ）実は　そうなんですよ。
そんなことも分かるの？！
It's really true!
You even figured that out?
こいつは　また
とんでもねえ　パズル好きだ。
We've found another puzzle maniac.
パズル？　う～ん
あんまり興味ないかも。
はぁ？！
Puzzles?
I don't think I'm interested.
でも　シュバシュバの絵なら
すっごく興味ある。
But I'm really interested in Schwa-Schwa's paintings!
シュバシュバ？
何だ　それ？
Schwa-Schwa?
Who's that?
シュバルツェンベルク。　ソウジが言ってた。
Schwarzenberg. Souji talked about it.
アナとカイトが行くのは
シュバシュバの家だって。
That Kaito and I are going to Schwa-Schwa's house.
ちょっと　何　カイトのこと
呼び捨てに…。
Why are you calling Kaito by his given name?
I think Sunday will be lots of fun!
思うにアナ　楽しみなんだな
次の日曜が。
そのことだけどさ。　俺は　あんたと
一緒に行く気はねえから。
I wanna talk to you about that. I don't want to go with you.
分かった。
アナ　１人で行ってくる。
Okay. I'll go by myself then.
じゃなくて　財を封じた
パズルってのは　危険なんだ。
That's not what I'm saying! Puzzles with treasures sealed in them are dangerous!
うん　気をつけて行ってくる。
だから　行くのは　俺１人だ！
Okay, I'll be careful then.
I'm saying I'll be going alone!
どうして？
パートナーなんか　必要ねえ。
Why?
I don't need a partner or anything.
俺だけで十分だからだ。
分かったな。
I'm fine by myself. You got it?
うん。　じゃあ　現地集合で。
Yeah.
See you there then!
あんた　話　聞いてっか？
アナも　パートナー要らない。
Are you even listening?
I don't need a partner either.
あんたが　パートナーだろ。
パズル解くのに邪魔なんだよ。
That would make you my partner.
You'd just get in my way of solving the puzzle.
パズルは　やらない。　絵を見るだけ。
I don't care about the puzzle. I'll just look at the paintings.
That's what I mean! You'd get in the way!
This is crazy. Why is such a cutie his partner?
心の声
聞いてない。　あんな
かわいい子が　パートナーだなんて…。
But I want to see Schwa-Schwa's paintings!
This has nothing to do with Schwa-Schwa!
シュバシュバ　関係ねえから。
カイト　何か疲れてる？
You look so tired, Kaito.
誰のせいだ…。
And whose fault is that?
心の声
今ごろ　あの子と　２人っきり！
Right now...
He's alone...
with that girl!
…って　まずくない？
Isn't that bad?
でけえ屋敷だな！
This mansion is hella huge.
I think... it's Schwa-Schwa's house. Of course!
アナが思うに　シュバシュバの
おうちだもん　当然！
何　それ？
猫トモ。
What are you doing?
Catpals.
猫トモ？
猫の友達。
Catpals?
Cat friends.
パズルは　俺が解く。
余計な手出しは　すんなよ。
I'll solve the puzzle. Don't do anything.
しな～い。
（呼び鈴）
I won't!
（セバスチャン）ようこそ！
お待ち申し上げておりました。
Welcome. We have been awaiting your arrival.
どうぞ　こちらへ。
どうも。
あっ！　シュバシュバの絵だ！
This way please.
Thanks.
Ah!
Schwa-Schwa's painting!
おい！
Hey!
やっぱり　置いてくるべきだった。
お～！
I should've left her outside.
（ラウラ）まったく！
いつまで待たせる気なの？
How dare you make me wait so long!
当主　ラウラ・フレデリカ・シュバルツェンベルク様で
ございます。
My mistress, Madam Laura Frederica Schwarzenberg.
あなたたちが
バロンのところの生徒？
You are students from Baron's school?
あまり利口そうには
見えませんけど。
You do not seem that smart.
まっ　いいでしょう。
Well, it matters not.
解けるというなら
さっさと解いてちょうだい。
If you can solve it, do so quickly.
あのばあさんが
絵描きのシュバルツェンベルク？
ううん。
Is she the painter Schwarzenberg?
No.
（ラウラ）主人は亡くなったわ。
先月　飛行機事故で。
My husband died in a plane crash last month.
偉大なお方でいらっしゃいました。
He was a great man.
絵を描くしか　能のない
つまらない人でしたよ。
He was a boring man who only had talent for painting.
風景画の大家か何だか
知りませんが→
He was praised as a master of scenery painting and whatnot;
題材探しだといっては
世界中を飛び回って→
he was travelling all around the world looking for material.
帰ってくるのは　年に１度か２度。
He only returned home once or twice a year.
It makes no difference to me if he's alive or dead.
私にとっては　生きていようが
いまいが同じようなものだったわ。
自分の旦那だろう？　しかも
死んじゃった人を　そんなふうに。
He was your husband.
You shouldn't talk about a dead man like that.
あの人のことを
知りもしないくせに。
You know nothing of him.
奥様は少々　ツンデレの気が
おありでして　ご容赦ください。
My mistress is a bit of a tsundere, please be understanding.
ウン。
思うに　絵は　とてもすてきだった。
I think his paintings are great.
それだけですよ。
And that is all.
（セバスチャン）以来　ラウラ奥様が　この
お屋敷を引き継がれたのですが…。
Madam Laura has inherited this mansion.
（ラウラ）売りに出すことにしたのよ。
I've decided to sell it.
（セバスチャン）残念なことにございます。
That is sad indeed.
（ラウラ）残念なものですか！
こんな屋敷。
Sad? For this mansion?
いい思い出なんて　１つも
ありはしませんよ。
I do not have a single good memory about it.
But before we put it up for sale, the puzzle that the late master
ですが　人手に渡す前に　旦那様が
お残しになった財を封じてある→
set up to protect the treasures he left behind must be solved.
パズルを解いておかねばならないと。
（戸の開く音）
どうぞ　こちらへ。
This way.
The treasure is locked in the safe at the other end of the room.
（セバスチャン）財は　奥の金庫に
封じられております。
What's the treasure?
財は　何だ？
My husband died without telling us.
（ラウラ）あの人は　何も告げずに
逝ってしまったわ。
あなたたちにも　ちゃんと
配分は差し上げますよ。
But we shall give you an appropriate share.
２割で　いかが？　どうせ
ろくなものじゃないでしょうけど。
How about a fifth? I'm sure it's something foolish though.
（セバスチャン）いいえ　奥様。
旦那様のお残しになられた財は→
No, Madam. The late master's treasure is of great value.
大変価値のあるものにございます。
セバスチャン　あなた！
Sebastian, you...!
はい　存じ上げております。
Yes, I know.
なぜなら　旦那様のご命令で
このパズルを作ったのは→
As per your husband's orders, I was the one who created this puzzle.
この私めに　ございますゆえ。
それじゃ　あんたが今回の…。
So then you're...
はい。　ＰＯＧ所属の
ギヴァーにございます。
Indeed. A Giver from the POG.
（セバスチャン）この壁は
あなた方がパズルを解き→
This wall will not open until you solve the puzzle and retrieve the treasure from the safe.
金庫に封じられた財を
解放するまで開きません。
思うに…　アナたち
閉じ込められたってこと？
I think... we're locked in here.
だから　来るなって言っただろう！
（セバスチャン）それと…。
That's why I told you not to come!
Also...
ガス？！
（セバスチャン）そのガスは　空気より
重いので下からたまっていきます。
Gas?!
This gas is heavier than air, so it accumulates from the floor.
Your time limit is until you are overcome by the gas.
すなわち　タイムリミットは　お二人が
ガスの底に沈むまででございます。
命をもてあそぶパズル。
Another puzzle that endangers lives!
回想
（バロン）分かっているのは
君が　これからソルヴァーとして→
I know that you will fight the POG's Givers from now on.
ＰＯＧのギヴァーと戦うということ。
いや　戦ってもらいたい。
Rather, I would like you to.
The POG won't get away with this!
ＰＯＧ　許せねえ！
カイト。
Kaito?
まず　この部屋の何が
うん。
パズルなのかを見つけ出す！
First...
We have to find out what the puzzle in this room is.
どういうことです？　セバスチャン。
早く２人を出しておやりなさい。
What's the meaning of this, Sebastian?
Let them out right away.
あいにくですが…。
えっ？！
Sadly...
たとえ奥様でも　私どもの勝負を
邪魔立てすることは許しません！
I cannot allow even you to interfere with this, Madam.
However, if you still want to save them, you are capable doing so.
しかし　それでも　なおと
おっしゃるのなら→
奥様は　お二人を救うことが
できるはずでございますよ。
Your late husband said so.
生前　旦那様がおっしゃっていた
ではありませんか。
奥様ならば　パズルなど解かずとも
暗証番号をご存じだと。
Even if you cannot solve the puzzle, you know the code.
知らないわ　そんな番号。
本当に？
I don't know of any code!
Are you sure?
エッ。
お忘れになっているのでは？
Might it be you merely forgot?
それじゃ　ちょっと急ぐので
お先に失礼します！
I'll be leaving then!
危険だ。　賢者のパズル。
心の声
It's dangerous... The Sage Puzzle...
というか　アナ・グラム？！
美人で　スタイルよくて　肌もきれい！
And Ana Gram too!
She's such a hottie! She's got style too! And her skin's beautiful!
What?! You're kidding me!
（ギャモン）おお！おめえ　そんなもの…
おっと　こりゃ　ラッキー！
Where did you get such a thing?
Whoa, lucky!
（ギャモン）カイトが　賢者のパズルを
解いてるだと？！
そうなの。
Kaito is solving a Sage Puzzle?
Yeah.
何で　俺に依頼しねえんだよ？
軸川先輩のやつ。
Why don't I get any requests? That Jikugawa bastard.
とにかく急がないと　危険よね。
We should hurry or it'll get dangerous.
危険って　何が危険なんだよ。
なっ　何でもないから　急いで！
Dangerous? What?
No-Nothing, just hurry!
うわ～！　これは　ロラっちの絵。
ミケりゃん！　おお！　ルブぴ～！
Oh, this is Lora-chi's painting!
Miche-ryan! Oh, Rube-pi!
I have to figure out the code from the 15 pictures on the wall.
１５枚の絵から　暗証番号を導き出す
パズルか。
絵の並びに規則性があるとは
思えねえ。　だとしたら…。
It doesn't look like they're lined up in any particular order.
Then...
The frame's pattern...
この額の模様…。
同じように見えるが
４つの辺で違っている。
looks the same.
But the four sides are different.
そうか。　もしかしたら…。
I see. Could it be...
やっぱり外れる。　アナ！
壁の絵を外してくれ！
Yep, I can take them off!
Ana! Take the pictures off the wall!
あっ　全部？
そうだ。　急げ！　時間がない！
All of them?
Yeah! And make it quick!
うん　分かった。
（呼び鈴）
Uh, okay.
どうして　誰も出ないの？
Why isn't anyone answering?
怪しい…。　裏の方に回ったら
中が見えないかな？
It's suspicious.
Let's check the back, maybe we can see inside!
おい。　のぞきは　やばくねえか？
We shouldn't be peeking...
だって　危険なんだもん。　来て！
ああっ！　お　おう。
But they could be in danger! Come on!
あっ　ちょっと　強引に　強引…。
Wait, don't pull...
We couldn't remove these three.
外せなかった絵が　この３枚。
今度は　これを基準にして→
We have to set up the rest to match these.
The neighboring frames should have the same patterns.
額の模様が隣同士
同じになるように並び替える。
てめえの出る幕は　ねえぜ。
There's no need for you.
Okay!
よしっ！
Ana! The lady with the folded arms goes in the center!
アナ！　腕組み姉ちゃんの絵を
真ん中だ！
うん！
こいつは　ここ！
This one here.
コロたんは　真ん中。
Coro-tan goes in the middle.
よしっ。
Okay.
模様同士　全部合わさった！
これで何が分かる？
We matched all the frames.
What does it mean?
ミケりゃん　マネマネ　ミレミレー
デュラるん　ドラわわ　ドーミゅん。
Miche-ryan, Mane-Mane, Mille-Mille, Durerun,
Delawawa, Daumyun, Caravacchi,
カラヴァッち～　コロたん　クルクールベー
ルブぴ～！
Coro-tan, Culcurbe, Rube-pi...
そうか！
はい？！
Really?
Yeah.
なるほど。　アナが　パートナーだって
訳が分かったよ。
Now I know why you're my partner.
It's the first initial of the names of the painters.
作者の名前の頭文字だ。
えっ？！
あ～！　左から　Ｍ　Ｄ　Ｃ　Ｌ　Ｖだ。
From left to right: M D C L V.
やった～！
よしっ。
We did it!
Yeah!
あれ？
アルファベットは入力できないかな。
You can't input letters.
うっ！
残念。　どうする？
Too bad. What now?
分からねえ。
I don't know.
クソっ～！　こいつは…　このパズルは
こんなに解かれたがってるのに！
Shit! This puzzle wants to be solved so badly!
うっ！
分かるの？　パズルの気持ち。
Can you tell how it feels?
このパズルは　とても優しくて
温かいんだ。
This puzzle is kind and warm.
ばあさんは　旦那さんの事を
悪く言ってたけど→
The old lady was bad-mouthing her husband, but I don't believe her!
俺には信じらんねえ。
カイトは　ホントに　パズルが好きなんだね。
You really love puzzles, don't you?
約束したんだ。
俺は　絶対に　パズルを信じるって。
I made a promise that I'd believe in puzzles no matter what.
回想
（ルーク）
僕たちだけは　信じてあげよう。
We should at least believe...
パズルのことを。
in the puzzles, okay?
But it feels like you actually hated puzzles.
けど　なんだか　本当は
パズルのことが大嫌いな…。
そんな思いの
裏返しなんじゃないかなって→
And that you're trying to hide that feeling.
そんな気がする。
クソっ！　もう時間が？！　あっ？！
Dammit, we're running out of time!
Are you all right? If I'm too heavy just say so!
大丈夫？　無理なら言ってね。
無理じゃねえ。　で　どうだい？
It's all right! So, anything?
ダメ。　どこに　カイトがいるか
分からない。
Nothing. I can't see Kaito anywhere.
Go a bit further that way!
もう少し　あっちに行こう。
おう　おう。　あっ！
あ～！
Okay!
大丈夫？
大丈夫だ。
Are you all right?
I'm fine!
う～ん　やっぱり分からない。
I don't know...
戻ろう！
おっ！　おおおっ。　腱が…。
Let's go back!
Okay...
If you can't do it, just say so!
ホントに無理だったら　言ってよ。
無理じゃねえって！
I can!
あっ！　だっ！　どた！
ああ！
あはっ！　全然無理じゃないから。
I totally can!
アナ　動かなかった３枚の絵
作者の出身地は？
Ana, the painters of the pictures we couldn't move...
Where are they from?
Umm... Italy.
えっ？！　イタリア。
Then it's roman numerals!
やっぱり！　ローマ数字か！
ローマ数字？
Roman numerals?
In roman numerals,
ローマ数字では　Ｍは１，０００　Ｄは５００
Ｃが１００で　Ｌが５０。
M is 1000, D is 500, C is 100, L is 50, and V is 5.
そして　Ｖが５を表している。
その全てを足せば…。
If you add them up...
あなたたち　無事だったのね。
You're all right!
Yeah. We solved the puzzle.
ああ　パズルは解いた。
金庫室の暗証番号は　１６５５だ。
The code for the safe was 1655.
これが　あの人の宝…。
This is his treasure...
んっ？！
旦那様がお描きになった→
The very last painting of the late master.
最後の１枚です。
ずっと見てくれていたのですね。
He was always looking at me.
あの人。
My husband...
パリの小さなビストロで　私は店員。
あの人は　お客。
In a tiny bistro in Paris, I was a waitress, and he was a customer.
いつもお金がなくて
一番安いメニューを頼んでた。
He was poor and always ordered from our bargain menu.
それも　毎日。
He came every day.
But once, he did not show up for several days.
なのに　そんな彼が　何日も
来ないことがあって。
具合でも悪いんじゃないかって
心配して→
I was worried he might be sick,
いつものメニューを持って
アトリエを訪ねてみたの。
so I brought his favorite meal to his studio. And then...
そしたら…　あの人ったら
ピンピンしてて　そこに私の絵が。
He was sitting there perfectly well, with a portrait of me beside him.
「きっと　君は来るだろう」って
イタズラ好きの子供みたいに笑ってた。
He was laughing like a mischevious child,
saying, "I knew you'd come."
もう　あきれすぎて
怒るのも忘れて…　恋に落ちた。
I was so shocked I forgot to be angry and fell in love.
彼と私が結ばれた思い出の場所。
The place where we were bound together.
思い出のナンバー。
The number of memories.
若い頃の話よ。　昔々のお話。
My youthful days... The days that have long passed.
カイト様　アナ様　お見事でした。
Kaito, Ana, you have done well.
ギヴァーの使命とはいえ　ご無礼
心より　おわび申し上げます。
Even though I may be a Giver, I apologize for my rudeness.
I am glad the puzzle was solved, but nevertheless, poison gas?
でも　パズルが解けたから
いいようなものの　毒ガスだなんて。
誰が毒ガスなどと申しました。
えっ？！
Who said anything about poison gas?
舞台用のスモークでございますよ。
It was mere stage smoke.
なにせ　旦那様は　イタズラが
大好きでいらっしゃいましたから。
The late master truly loved mischief.
うっふ。
あんたのパズルは温かかった。
Your puzzle was really warm.
ＰＯＧにも
いろんなギヴァーがいるんだな。
I see there are many kinds of Givers in the POG.
依頼人の望みどおりのパズルを→
I merely built the puzzle as specified.
お作り申し上げただけで
ございます。
What's with that satisfied look on his face?
何？　あの充実しきった顔。
あっ　お前ら　何やってんだ？
こんなとこで。
What are you two doing here?
カ　カイトには関係ないでしょ。
まあ　何もなかったみてえだな。
It has nothing to do with you.
Yeah, looks like it was nothing.
そうだ　ノノハ　よかったら
俺が家まで送って…。
So Nonoha, should I take you home?
Did you have fun, Ana?
アナちゃんは　楽しかったの？
うん。　アナが思うに→
I think... it was really fun!
とっても楽しかった！
ふ～ん！　カイトは？
And you, Kaito?
ああ　久々に　いい気分だぜ。
ふっ　ふ～ん！
Yeah, it's been a while since I felt this good.
（ビショップ）いかが　いたしましょう？
What should we do?
（ルーク）慌てることはない。
There's nothing to worry about.
お手並み拝見と
いこうじゃないか。
I think we should go and visit him.
いよいよだね　カイト。
The time has come, Kaito.
WHAT?!
あっ　あっ！
アッ　アナって　男の子？
A-Ana... You're a guy?
そうだよ。　それより　パズルって
面白い！　前言撤回！
Yeah. And puzzles are so much fun!
I take back what I said earlier!
なっ…。
男って　マジかよ？！
You're a guy? Seriously?
すてきな人に　いっぱい会えたし。
中でも　カイト！
I met lots of great people!
Especially you, Kaito!
ああっ　うわ～っ！
ちょっと！　いや　男　男…。
Hey!
Wait, he's a he, he's a he...
ありがとう　カイト。
Thank you, Kaito.
（２人）おっ　男。
He's a he...
tsukue no ue de umareta sekai
This world born on my table.
ichiban saki ni kimi ni misetakatta
I wanted you to see it first.
karappo no heya sotto nukedashite hashiri hajimeteta
I sneaked out of the empty room and started to run.
iki hazamasete oka wo noboru to
As I got to the top of the hill, out of breath,
kimi ga saki ni tsuite matteita ne
you were already there waiting for me.
takusan no hajimete kimi to mitsuketa takaramono datta
It was the first of many treasures we would find together.
kanashisa de afureta toki wa
When sorrow was overflowing in me,
nanimo iwazu ni tada soba ni ite kureta ne
you just silently stayed by my side.
ima de mo wasurenai yo
I still haven't forgotten that.
mata aou ne yakusoku wo shiyou
Let's promise we'll meet again.
kie wa shinai ano hi no sayonara
The goodbye of that day we'll never forget.
boku no subete kimi ga kureta michi
All I have I got from you,
zutto kokoro no naka hikaru yo
and it will all shine in my heart forever.